[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：拯救的函数式编程。
&gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Functional Programming to the Rescue.
所以四年后函数式编程突然变得
So one of the reasons why after four years, Functional Programming is suddenly
变得重要是因为它包含了这些问题的解决方案。
become important is because it contains the solutions to these problems.
我们在这方面有很多历史。
And we've got a lot of history with this stuff.
回到来自数据流和LISP的未来，未来是一个对象
And going back to future which came out of Dataflow and LISP, future is an object
这代表了一些尚不可知的东西，但可能是在未来。
which represents something which isn't knowable yet, but might be in the future.
因此，您可以开始与未来对象进行交互，最终它将
So you can begin interacting with the future object, and eventually it will
向任何人传达你的兴趣，无论答案是什么。
communicate your interest to whatever the answer turns out to be.
期货对一个叫做承诺的功能有很大的影响。
Futures had a big influence on a feature called Promises.
承诺是在我创立的一家公司里发现的，这个公司叫做
Promises were discovered in a company that I founded called
电子社区的一种语言，我们称之为E。
Electric Communities for a language that we called E.
承诺后来从E逃出来，转移到Python和
Promises have since escaped from E and moved into Python and
然后进入JavaScript，不幸的是，它们发生了很大的变异。
then into JavaScript where unfortunately they've mutated kind of badly.
但仍然有一个非常有趣的机制
But there's still a really interesting mechanism for
管理分布式系统中的异步性。
managing asynchronicity in distributed systems.
上门服务社区已经开始使用Monads和Arrows，
The house call community has begun to Monads, and Arrows,
微软有一种叫做RX的东西，反应性扩展
Microsoft has something called RX, reactive extensions which
允许组成事件流，非常有趣的东西。
allows for composing of events streams, very interesting stuff.
不幸的是，它从来没有被记录准确或
Unfortunately it's never been documented accurate or
有充分的记录。&gt；&gt；演讲者2：我们确实有一门课程
documented sufficiently. &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: We do have a course by which
基本上涵盖了可观察到的模式以及RX和是如何工作的一切。
covers essentially the observable pattern and how RX and are working everything.
只是把它扔出去。&gt；&gt；Douglas Crockford：是的。
Just throwing it out there. &gt;&gt; Douglas Crockford: Yeah.
是好东西。
It's good stuff.
只是我不会用它，因为如果我把它投入生产，
It's just I wouldn't use it because if I'm putting it into production,
我想知道它是如何工作的，但它给了我灵感。
I want to know how it works but it's been inspirational.
它创造了一种新的编程形式，称为函数式反应编程和
It's created a new form of programming called Functional Reactive Programming and
例子包括煎饼，培根和元素等。
examples include Flapjacks, bacon, and element, and others.
但我突然意识到这份清单还不够长。
But occurred to me that this list just isn't long enough.
我正在给它添加我自己的东西，那就是一个叫做RQ的库。
I'm adding my own thing to it and that is a library called RQ.
RQ是一个用于管理异步性和服务器应用程序的库。
RQ is a library for managing asynchronicity and server applications.
区别于我提到的其他东西的是，
The thing that distinguishes it from the others that I mention,
这个是专门为您在服务器中所做的而设计的。
is that this one was designed specifically for what you do in servers.
其他人都不是。
None of the other ones were.
一切都可以工作，但我认为
Everything can be made to work but I think for
你在服务器上做的这一个会更好地为你工作。
what you do in servers this one is gonna work better for you.
RQ是一个非常小的库，它只包含四个或
RQ is a very small library, that only contains four or
五种方法取决于你如何计数。
five methods depending on how you count.
如果你用Java计数，它是5，如果你用JavaScript计数，它是4。
If you count in Java, it's five, if you count in JavaScript, it's four.
所以让我们来看看这四个，因为一旦你完成了这四个功能，
So let's look at the four, cuz once you do these four functions,
这就是整件事。
that's the whole thing.
所以一个序列需要一个请求者函数的数组，并且
So a sequence takes an array of requester functions and
返回一个函数，该函数一次调用它们一个
returns a function that will call them one at a time
将前一个请求者的结果传递给下一个请求者。
passing the result of the previous requestor to the next requestor.
例如，这里我们将创建一个getnav请求器，它将首先读取文件，
Here for example we're gonna make a getnav requestor which will first read the file,
然后获得首选项，然后获得自定义导航。
and then get the preference, and then get the custom nav.
然后我们可以并行地做事情。
Then we can do things in parallel.
现在我们没有向JavaScript添加并行性，我们所做的是，
Now we're not adding parallelism to JavaScript, what we're doing is,
允许JavaScript利用宇宙的自然并行性。
allowing JavaScript to exploit the natural parallelism of the universe.
因为很可能您将调用不同的服务
Cuz it's likely that you're gonna be calling services that are in different
盒子或不同的网络。
boxes or different networks.
一切都在宇宙中流逝，一直在异步运行，所以
It's all going out in the universe, runs asynchronously all the time so
你可以利用这一点。
you get to take advantage of that.
在这里，我们将创建一个Get Stuff构造函数，
Here we're gonna make a get stuff constructor which will,
当它被称为获得导航，获得广告和获得每日信息，
when it's called get the Nav, get the Ads and get the Message Of The Day,
它会一下子把他们都弄到手。
it will get them all at once.
这样做的成本将是这三个中最慢的一个。
The cost of this will be whichever of these three is the slowest.
那么我们也可以有可选的东西。
Then we can also have optional things.
我们可以提供第二组可选的东西。
We can provide a second array of optional things.
我们也会去拿星座和八卦，但我们不会等
We will also go and get the horoscope and the gossip but we will not wait for
如果他们没有，如果这十二个人中的任何一个在主要的三个之前完成
those if they don't if either of those dozen complete before the main three
完成后，我们只需取消它们，然后带着已完成的内容返回。
complete, we'll just cancel them and return with whatever has been finished.
我们可以处理种族问题。
We can deal with races.
这些都是好的种族。
These are the good kinds of races.
我们可以一次开始几件事
We can start several things at once and
不管第一个成功完成的是哪一个，那就是我们得到的那个。
whichever the first one to finish successfully, that's the one we get.
我们的广告网络可能有问题。
We might be having trouble with our Ad network.
我们正在处理三个广告网络，它们都太慢了。
We're dealing with three Ad networks and they're all too slow.
我们告诉他们，我们会有一场比赛。
We tell them, we're gonna have a race.
无论何时我们有了职位，我们都会问你和你的两个竞争对手，并且
Whenever we have a position, we will ask you and two of your competitors, and
谁先回来拿到合适的位置就会赢。
whoever comes back first with a suitable placement will win.
我们也可以处理后备，所以我们可以尝试一件事。
We can also deal with fallbacks, so we can try one thing.
如果失败了，我们再试一次。
If that fails, we'll try another.
我们要这样做来适应我们的天气。
We're gonna do that to get on our weather.
我们将首先转到本地缓存。
We'll first go to our local Cache.
如果失败，我们将转到我们的localDB。
If that fails, we'll go to our localDB.
如果失败，我们将转到remoteDB。
If that fails, we go to the remoteDB.
现在理论上，获得天气的最快方法是进行一场比赛，但是
Now in theory, the fastest way to get the weather would be to have a race, but
拥有这种等级制度的整个意义在于我们想要
the whole point of having this kind of hierarchy is that we want to go to
remoteDB只是作为最后的手段，而回退允许我们这样做。
the remoteDB only as a last resort, and fall backs allow us to do that.
就是这样，这就是RQ的全部指标。
That's it, that's the whole metrics for RQ.
我们可以一次启动所有请求者，也可以一次启动一个请求者，
We can start all the requesters at once, or we can start them one at a time,
然后我们可以得到一个结果或者我们可以得到所有的结果。
and then we can then take one result or we can take all of the results.